<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Amazonian</name>
		<update version="0.2.2">
			<file name="race-amazonian.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/pisithsork/Aurora-Custom-Build/master/race-amazonian.index" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Amazonian" type="Race" source="User" id="ID_RACE_AMAZONIAN">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">To be greeted with stares and whispers, to suffer violence and insult on the street, to see mistrust and fear in every eye: this is the lot of the tiefling. And to twist the knife, tieflings know that this is because a pact struck generations ago infused the essence of Asmodeus—overlord of the Nine Hells—into their bloodline. Their appearance and their nature are not their fault but the result of an ancient sin, for which they and their children and their children’s children will always be held accountable.</p>
			<h4>PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION</h4>
			<p>Amazons are large, well-built humanoids with powerful builds. They are entirely female, and a member of any race would find them beautiful. Their skin colors are as varied as humans' are, ranging from incredibly dark-skinned to borderline transparent, and their hair usually tends to be white, black, or gray.</p>
			<p>Amazons reproduce somewhat rarely, by praying to their gods with extravagant feasts and revels. The morning after a successful ceremony, a baby amazon will be found somewhere nearby, in a cradle-shaped tree or shrub of golden leaves and vines, apparently sprung from out the ground. Leaves from these Vinecradles are often kept by the amazon throughout their lives, whether sewn into clothes, worn in their hair, or gilded to weapons. There is also a myth among amazons, that those sisters of gloomy temperament are first found on rainy or overcast mornings. Typically, an amazon will have two or more volunteer-mothers, but in truth are raised by the whole tribe together. Rarely, amazons can also be born from relationships with other races, though they will often face mild prejudice from their sisters. Indeed to this day, no known Amazonian Queen has been born this way.</p>
			<h4>PERSONALITY</h4>
			<p>Amazons are a very proud but kindhearted sharing race. They often spend their time together crafting or decorating their armor, making food, and most commonly playing sports such as goatball which they took from their goliath allies. Amazons also love to hunt for sport and pull the occasional prank.</p>
			<h4>TIEFLING NAMES</h4>
			<p>Amazonian names draw primarily from the ancient Greek and as such Latin naming schemes. Xanathar's Guide to Everything has a section that gives the player a rollable table of 50 female Greek names on page 186.</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Names:</strong> Aello, Ainia, Ainippe, Alcinoe, Alkaia, Bremusa, Celaneo, Clete, Clyemne, Deianeira, Diana, Doris, Echephyle, Eumache, Euryleia, Harmothoe, Iphito, Kydoime, Lykopis, Lysippe, Molpadia, Okyale, Prothoe, Pyrgomache, Tecmessa, Thraso, Toxaris, Valasca, Xanthippe</li>
			</ul>
			<h4>AMAZONIAN TRAITS</h4>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Strength, Constitution, and Charsima scores each increase by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Amazons reach adulthood in their mid-teens, and usually live to be just over 200 years old. Their body's showing no sign of age until their final years.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Amazons usually tend toward lawfl alignments, as their outlook takes influence from their goliath allies.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Amazons typically stand roughly between 6 and 8 feet tall and weigh between 200 and 340 pounds. Your size is Medium</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 35 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Amazon Weapon Training.</em></strong> You have proficiency with spears, glaives, shortbows, longbows, and shields.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Earthborn.</em></strong> Amazons, being sculpted and born from the ground are said to be as strong and as reslient as the earth. Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Powerful Build.</em></strong> Your peoples emphasize on self-betterment and your naturally adept body causes you to be significantly stronger than most races your size. You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Rugged Grace.</em></strong> Amazons have an inherent, nigh-deific, yet somewhat uncivilized presence that other races take note of. Whether this takes the form of noble gesture, bombastic charm or feminine sway, their unusual mannerisms, intentionally or otherwise, fill others' perceptions with warm feelings and clouded judgment. Whenever you make an Charisma (Persuasion) or an Charisma (Intimidation) check against a humanoid creature, you are considered proficient in the Persuasion or Intimidation skill and if you are already proficient you may add double your proficiency bonus to the check, instead of your normal proficiency bonus.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Common and Giant.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="female">Aello, Ainia, Ainippe, Alcinoe, Alkaia, Bremusa, Celaneo, Clete, Clyemne, Deianeira, Diana, Doris, Echephyle, Eumache, Euryleia, Harmothoe, Iphito, Kydoime, Lykopis, Lysippe, Molpadia, Okyale, Prothoe, Pyrgomache, Tecmessa, Thraso, Toxaris, Valasca, Xanthippe</set>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d12">6'0"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="2d6">200 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength" value="1" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_AMAZONIAN_SUBRACE" />
			<stat name="constitution" value="1" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_AMAZONIAN_SUBRACE"/>
			<stat name="charisma" value="1" requirements="
				!ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_AMAZONIAN_SUBRACE" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="35" bonus="base"/>
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_GIANT" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AMAZON_WEAPON_TRAINING" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_EARTHBORN" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_GOLIATH_POWERFUL_BUILD"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_RUGGED_GRACE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Amazon Weapon Training" type="Racial Trait" source="user" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_AMAZON_WEAPON_TRAINING">
		<description>
			<p>You have proficiency with spears, glaives, shortbows, longbows, and shields.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have proficiency with spears, glaives, shortbows, longbows, and shields.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SPEARS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_GLAIVES" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTBOWS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGBOWS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHIELD" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Earthborn" type="Racial Trait" source="user" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_EARTHBORN">
		<description>
			<p>Amazons, being sculpted and born from the ground are said to be as strong and as resilient as the earth. Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your max hit points is increased by {{earthborn:hp}}.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="earthborn:hp" value="level" />
			<stat name="hp" value="earthborn:hp" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Rugged Grace" type="Racial Trait" source="user" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_RUGGED_GRACE">
		<description>
			<p>Amazons have an inherent, nigh-deific, yet somewhat uncivilized presence that other races take note of. Whether this takes the form of noble gesture, bombastic charm or feminine sway, their unusual mannerisms, intentionally or otherwise, fill others' perceptions with warm feelings and clouded judgment.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever you make an Charisma (Persuasion) or an Charisma (Intimidation) check against a humanoid creature, you are considered proficient in the Persuasion or Intimidation skill and if you are already proficient you may add double your proficiency bonus to the check, instead of your normal proficiency bonus.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
